# Katrina Butler

301-2055 York Ave, Vancouver, BC, Canada, V6J 1E5 613-297-7290 kat.a.butler@gmail.com

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I am a Software Developer with professional experience in mobile and front-end development, enthusiastic about new technologies, and am always excited to start new projects. I am an innovative individual with excellent communication and interpersonal skills. If I'm not engaged in my personal projects, you can find me hiking and taking photos.

### **EDUCATION**

### **Carleton University:**

Graduated with a Bachelor of Computer Science

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Software Developer @ Zaui Software: May 2014 - Present

- Developed new iOS app for iOS 7 & iOS 8 using Swift
- Developing new Android app using Java
- Developed features/fixed bugs for iPad Point of Sale app using Objective-C
- Integrated different devices for apps (cash drawer, credit card swipers, Epson & Star receipt printers, Zebra printer)
- Managed distribution of iPhone and iPad apps to customers using In-House Enterprise Distribution
- Presented and demoed new iOS app at Zaui Connect Conference
- Implemented features/fixed bugs in Zaui API, Back-End, and Front-End using PHP, JavaScript, and MySQL
- Created/Designed mockups, prototypes, and UIs for new Android/iOS apps
- Conducted the transition from CVS to Git

### Contract Web Developer @ Trilogy North America: August 2013 - November 2013

Worked with small team developing a webapp for Trilogy North America:

- Created UI mockups and reviewed design decisions directly with client
- Developed webapp using Ruby on Rails web application framework
- Designed database schema to manage text and media to be used throughout site
- Developed front-end ERB HTML views
- Used ¡Query for Ajax calls to the server

# Junior Software Developer @ N-able Technologies: May 2013 – August 2013

Worked with UI team and project managers on migrating SDK app to N-Central UI:

- Developed JSP pages using Apache Struts 2, HTML, and Dojo
- Developed pages in UI using Java, JavaScript, Dojo, and XML
- Tested and debugged UI pages across multiple browsers
- Presented formal demos to team members, project managers, and product manager

# Junior UI Developer @ N-able Technologies: May 2012 – August 2012

Worked with UI team on the N-Central software (RMM and MSP Service Automation Platform):

- Converted JavaScript codebase (using dojo version 1.6) to AMD format (dojo version 1.7+)
- Developed pages in the UI using Java, XML, and JavaScript
- Converted pages using Apache Struts 2 (previously developed in Struts 1)

# Junior Software Developer @ N-able Technologies: May 2011 – August 2011

Worked in a team environment on various projects including:

- Bug fixes: User Interfaces and reports using C#, XML, ASP.NET, and SQL
- Worked with Quality Assurance team testing UI, reports, and other areas
- Converted legacy reports from SQL stored procedures to new data model
- Developed user manuals and tutorials

## LANGUAGES, SKILLS, AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Software Development, iOS/Android Development, Agile Methodologies, Web Development, User Interface Design, Mobile Design
- Objective-C, Swift, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, XML, C++, C
- iOS Sprite Kit, Hibernate, Dojo, Struts, SQLite, Node.js
- Git, Xcode, Sublime Text, Eclipse, Qt Creator, Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator
- MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite
- Mac OS X, Linux, Ubuntu, Windows

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### RoamBot:

- Worked in a team of four and participated in Great Canadian Appathon 4
- Created a mobile game in 48 hours for iOS 7
- Used iOS Sprite Kit framework to create the game

### bebop:

- Android app which allows you to stream music from services such as Spotify and Rdio to use as alarms